Guide to the Dwight Macdonald Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Miscellany, 1865-(1916-1977); Series VI; 5 linear feet (12 boxes)
  - Photographs
    - Theodore Dwight Macdonald, 1874, 1878-1879, 1883, 1887, 1897, [1915], undated (Box 163, Folder 48)
    - Dwight Macdonald, 1906-1919, 1920-1924, 1924-1928, [1930s-1940s], [1950s], [1960s] (Box 163, Folder 50-56)
    - Dwight Macdonald: formal portraits, [1960s] (Box 163, Folder 57)
    - Dwight Macdonald: group pictures, [1960s] (Box 163, Folder 58)
    - Dwight Macdonald, [1970s] (Box 164, Folder 59)
    - Hedges Macdonald, 1908, 1918, 1920, 1922-1924, 1926, 1936, 1938, 1943, undated (Box 164, Folder 60)
    - Nancy Rodman Macdonald, 1935, undated (Box 164, Folder 61)
    - Michael Macdonald, 1939, 1952 (Box 164, Folder 62)
    - Nicholas G. Macdonald, 1945-1946, 1952, 1956-1957, [1962?] (Box 164, Folder 63)
    - Nicholas G. Macdonald and Elspeth Macdonald, 1965 (Box 164, Folder 64)
    - Gloria Macdonald, [1956-1957], 1968, undated (Box 164, Folder 65)
    - Mary Day Lanier, undated (Box 164, Folder 66)
    - Other relatives, undated (Box 164, Folder 67)
    - Abel, Lionel, [1944-1949] (Box 164, Folder 68)
    - Agee, James, 1933 (Box 164, Folder 68)
    - Coffin, William Sloane
      See: box 29, folder 753
    - Dupee, Frederick W., [1924], [1928] (Box 164, Folder 68)
    - Fry, Roger, [1961?] (Box 164, Folder 68)
    - Hutchins, Robert M., undated (Box 164, Folder 69)
    - Lowell, Robert, [1964] (Box 164, Folder 69)
    - Lukacs, John, [1965] (Box 164, Folder 69)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1958 (Box 164, Folder 69)
    - Manheim, Ralph and Mary, [1956-1957?] (Box 164, Folder 69)
    - Schwartz, Delmore, 1965, undated (Box 164, Folder 70)
    - Trotsky, Leon, undated (Box 164, Folder 70)
    - Wheeler, Dinsmore, 1923, [1924], undated (Box 164, Folder 71)
    - Wheeler, Dorothy, undated (Box 164, Folder 71)
    - Wheeler, Robert, 1966 (Box 164, Folder 71)
    - World War II (used in politics ), [1940s] (Box 164, Folder 72)
    - Miscellaneous, 1947, 1962, 1969-1970, undated (Box 164, Folder 73)
    - Silhouettes of Dwight Macdonald and Hedges Macdonald, [1920-1921] (Box 164, Folder 74)
    - Drawings of Dwight Macdonald, [1957?], undated (Box 164, Folder 75)
  - Schwartz Estate
    - A - E: correspondence (Box 165, Folder 76)
    - Atlas, James: correspondence, drafts annotated by D. Macdonald, 1974-1977 (Box 165, Folder 77)
    - Brunner, George F.: correspondence, 1975 (Box 165, Folder 78)
    - Buckman, Gertrude
      See: box 45, folder 1118
    - Colle, Clara: correspondence, 1966 (Box 165, Folder 78)
    - Dike, Donald: correspondence, drafts annotated by D. Macdonald, 1967-1971, 1977 (Box 165, Folder 79)
    - Doubleday & Company, Inc.: correspondence, 1970, 1977 (Box 165, Folder 79)
    - F - P: correspondence (Box 165, Folder 80)
    - Farrar, Straus & Giroux, Inc.: correspondence, 1967-1968, 1970, 1976-1977 (Box 165, Folder 81)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert: correspondence, 1966 (Box 165, Folder 81)
    - Herbst, Josephine: correspondence, 1966 (Box 165, Folder 82)
    - Howe, Irving: correspondence, 1966-1968, 1975-1976 (Box 165, Folder 82)
    - Lowell, Robert: correspondence, 1966 (Box 165, Folder 82)
    - Macdonald, Dwight: clippings, notes, 1966-1977 (Box 165, Folder 83)
    - Macdonald, Dwight: drafts, 1966, [1976] (Box 165, Folder 84)
    - Moss, Howard
      See: box 37, folder 933
    - The New York Review of Books: letter, 1966 (Box 165, Folder 85)
    - The New Yorker: correspondence, 1975 (Box 165, Folder 86)
    - Phillips, Robert: correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 165, Folder 86)
    - Pollet, Elizabeth
      See: box 45, folder 1117
    - Q - Z: correspondence (Box 165, Folder 87)
    - Schapiro, Meyer: correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 165, Folder 88)
    - Schwartz, Elizabeth Pollet (Mrs. Delmore): correspondence, 1966, [1967?] (Box 165, Folder 89)
    - Schwartz, Gertrude Buckman: correspondence, 1966-1967, [1969?] 1975 (Box 165, Folder 90)
    - Schwartz, Kenneth: correspondence, 1966-1969, 1971, 1975-1976 (Box 165, Folder 91)
    - Syracuse University: correspondence, 1976 (Box 165, Folder 92)
      See also: box 191, folder 18 box 165, folder 79
    - University of Chicago Press: financial papers, 1971, 1974 (Box 165, Folder 92)
    - Valenti, Lee: correspondence, drafts, 1970-1971, 1974 (Box 165, Folder 93)
    - Yale University Library: correspondence, 1974-1975, 1977 (Box 165, Folder 94)
  - Legal and Financial
    - Wills of: Ada L. Shiland, 1915, 1940, 1955 (Box 165, Folder 95)
    - Alice Hedges Macdonald (Box 165, Folder 95)
    - George B. Hedges (Box 165, Folder 95)
    - Papers related to stock purchases and other matters, 1928-1939 (Box 165, Folder 96)
    - Papers related to the settlement of family estates, 1930-1948 (Box 165, Folder 97)
    - Papers related to insurance, 1931-1964 (Box 165, Folder 98)
    - Wills of Dwight Macdonald, 1935-1964 (Box 165, Folder 99)
    - Papers related to stock purchases, payments from The New Yorker and other matters, 1940-1949, undated (Box 165, Folder 100)
    - Correspondence about schooling for Michael and Nicholas Macdonald, 1946-1964 (Box 166, Folder 101)
    - Papers related to the settlement of family estates, payments from The New Yorker, and other matters, 1950-1959 (Box 166, Folder 102)
    - Checks and monthly statements of Alice Hedges Macdonald, 1953-1956 (Box 166, Folder 103)
    - Account of receipts and payments for Alice Hedges Macdonald, 1957 (Box 166, Folder 103)
    - Divorce agreements between Nancy and Dwight Macdonald and Gloria and Robert Lanier, 1954 (Box 166, Folder 104)
    - Correspondence about support for the Lanier children, 1956-1957 (Box 166, Folder 104)
    - Household bills, 1958-1962 (Box 166, Folder 105)
    - Papers related to payments from The New Yorker and other matters, 1960-1969 (Box 166, Folder 106)
    - Papers related to income and taxes, 1964-1965 (Box 166, Folder 107)
    - Letters, 1971, 1973 (Box 166, Folder 108)
    - Application for unemployment compensation with covering memorandum by D. Macdonald, 1977 (Box 166, Folder 108)
    - Cancelled checks and check stubs, 1953-1969 (Box 167, Folder 109)
  - Travel
    - Europe: bills, menu, 1933, 1935 (Box 168, Folder 110)
    - Milan Conference on "The Future of Freedom": brochures, personal documents, miscellaneous printed matter, 1955 (Box 168, Folder 111)
    - Europe: theater programs, brochures, bills, itinerary, 1956-1957 (Box 168, Folder 112)
    - France and Italy: maps, personal documents, brochures, bills, 1957 (Box 168, Folder 113)
    - Europe: records of daily expense, 1957-1958 (Box 168, Folder 114)
    - England: diary (Apr 29-May 3), itinerary, personal documents, brochures, bills, menus, unidentified letters, 1959 (Box 168, Folder 115)
    - England: memorandum book, 1959 (Box 168, Folder 116)
    - Europe: theater programs, shipboard publications, 1960-1961 (Box 168, Folder 117)
    - Europe: financial papers, miscellaneous printed matter, 1960-1961 (Box 169, Folder 118)
    - New Orleans: bills, menus, brochures, 1962 (Box 169, Folder 119)
    - Europe, "Take Abroad": itineraries, brochures, clippings, 1964 (Box 169, Folder 120)
    - Europe: bills, brochures, 1964 (Box 169, Folder 121)
    - Mexico City: menus, maps, personal documents, miscellaneous printed matter, 1966 (Box 169, Folder 122)
    - Germany (1967)
      See: box 111, folder 542
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963, undated (Box 169, Folder 123)
  - Annotated volumes
    - Agee, James and Evans, Walker, Let Us Now Praise Famous Men, 1970 (Box 188)
    - Bazon, André, What is Cinema?, 1967 (Box 188)
    - Carter, Joan and Pollard, Graham
      - An Enquiry into the Nature of Certain Nineteenth Century Pamphlets, 1934 (Box 188)
      - Coleridge's Literary Criticism, with an introduction by J. W. Mackail, 1949 (Box 188)
    - De Vilallonga, José Luis, The Pleasure Seeker, 1962 (Box 188)
    - Dos Passos, John The Big Money (Box 188)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, The Great Gatsby, 1925 (Box 188)
    - Hall, Robert A., Jr., Linguistics and Your Language, 1960 (Box 188)
    - Hawthorne, Nathaniel
      - The Blithedale Romance, 1968 (Box 188)
      - The Celestial Railroad and Other Stories, 1963 (Box 188)
      - English Men of Letters, edited by John Morley: "Hawthorne," by Henry James, Jr., 1879 (Box 188)
      - Hawthorne: A Collection of Critical Essays, edited by A. N. Kaul, 1966 (Box 188)
      - Selected Tales and sketches, introduction by Hyatt H. Waggoner, 1960 (Box 188)
    - Henderson, Robert M. D. W Griffith: The Years at Biograph, 1970 (Box 188)
    - Herzen, Alexander vols.I - IV My Past and Thoughts, 1968 (Box 188)
    - McCarthy, Mary, The Company She Keeps, 1942 (Box 189)
    - Mailer. Norman, The Armies of the Night, 1968 (Box 189)
    - Marx, Karl, Capital: A Critique of Political Economy, 1934 (Box 189)
    - Melville, Herman
      - A Collection of Critical Essays, edited by Richard Chase, 1962 (Box 189)
      - Great Short stories of Melville, 1970 (Box 189)
    - Nietzche, Friedrich, The Use and Abuse of History, 1949 (Box 189)
    - Petrement, Simone, Simone Weil: A Life, 1976 (Box 189)
    - Poe, Edgar Allen Complete Short Stories and Poems, 1966
      - Edgar Allen Poe, edited by Philip Van Doren Stern (Box 189)
      - Edgar Allen Poe: Representative Selections, by Margaret Alterton and Hardin Craig, 1969 (Box 189)
      - The Enigma of Poe, edited by Warren Ober et al, 1960 (Box 189)
      - Literary Criticism of Edgar Alien Poe, edited by Robert L. Hough, 1965 (Box 189)
      - Poe: A Collection of Critical Essays, edited by Robert Regan, 1967 (Box 189)
      - Poe: Journalist and Critic, by Robert D. Jacobs, 1969 (Box 189)
      - The Poems of Edgar Allen Poe, edited by Killis Campbell, 1962 (Box 189)
      - Selected Writings of Edgar Allen Poe, edited by Edward H. Davidson, 1956 (Box 189)
    - Roth, Philip: Reading Myself and Others, 1975 (Box 189)
    - Schary, Dore: Lonelyhearts, 1958 (Box 190)
    - Seton, Marie Sergei M. Eisenstein, undated (Box 190)
    - Talbot, Daniel, ed. Film: An Anthology, 1967 (Box 190)
    - Warren, Robert Penn All the King's Men, 1968 (Box 190)
- Previously Restricted, 1920-1978
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Correspondence
    - Colebrook, Joan, 1949-1954, 1956-1957 (Box 170, Folder 124)
    - Macdonald, Elspeth Woodcock, 1965 (Box 170, Folder 125)
    - Macdonald, Gloria, 1951- [1973?] (Box 170, Folder 126-128)
    - Macdonald, Nicholas, 1965 (Box 170, Folder 129)
    - Manheim, Kate, 1970, 1972 (Box 170, Folder 130)
    - Meck, Dorothy Wheeler, 1925-1936, 1939, 1945-1946, 1948-1955, 1958-1965, undated (Box 170, Folder 131-148)
    - Medical, 1948, 1956, 1959, 1960 (Box 170, Folder 149)
  - Topical files
    - Divorce, [1951?]- 1954 (Box 170, Folder 150)
    - The National Institute of Arts and Letters and the American Academy of Arts and Letters (Awards Committee transactions): research material, notes, correspondence, 1969-1978 (Box 170, Folder 151-154)
  - Writings
    - Journal, 1928-1943, 1951 (Box 170, Folder 155-156)
    - Journal notes, 1920-1953, 1972 (Box 170, Folder 157)
    - Poetry, 1947 (Box 170, Folder 158)
- Additional Material, Accession 1985-M-006
  - Correspondence
    - A - B, 1950-1981, undated (Box 171, Folder 1-2)
    - "Ben Hur", 1961 (Box 171, Folder 3)
    - C, 1962-1981, undated (Box 171, Folder 4-5)
    - Crowell, Thomas Y. Company, 1963-1965 (Box 171, Folder 6)
    - D, 1971-1980 (Box 171, Folder 7)
    - Dixon, Kent H., 1980 (Box 171, Folder 8)
    - Dupee, Frederick Wilcox, 1927-1979, undated (Box 171, Folder 9)
    - E - G, 1945-1982, undated (Box 171, Folder 10-12)
    - Greenfield, Myrna, 1976, 1978 (Box 171, Folder 13)
    - H - L, 1958-1982, undated (Box 171, Folder 14-19)
    - Lowenthal, Leo, 1953 (Box 171, Folder 20)
    - Lukacs, John, 1972-1980 (Box 171, Folder 21)
    - M, 1963-1980, undated (Box 172, Folder 22-23)
    - McDonald, Hedges Jr., 1978 (Box 172, Folder 24)
    - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1965 (Box 172, Folder 25)
    - N, 1975, 1980, undated (Box 172, Folder 26)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1976, 1978 (Box 172, Folder 27)
    - 0, 1978, 1980 (Box 172, Folder 28)
    - P, 1951-1980, undated (Box 172, Folder 29-30)
    - R, 1960-1979, undated (Box 172, Folder 31-32)
    - Radash, Ronald, 1977-1978 (Box 172, Folder 33)
    - S, 1942-1981, undated (Box 172, Folder 34-35)
    - Schwartz, Delmore, 1942, 1971 (Box 172, Folder 36)
    - SCUM manifesto, 1968 (Box 172, Folder 37)
    - Students for a Democratic Society, 1968 (Box 172, Folder 38)
    - T, 1961-1971, undated (Box 172, Folder 39)
    - V, 1931, 1980 (Box 172, Folder 40)
    - Yannella, Don, 1971 (Box 172, Folder 41)
    - Unidentified, 1975-1982, undated (Box 172, Folder 42)
    - W, 1931-1982 (Box 172, Folder 43)
  - Research and writing
    - Yale publications, 1927 (Box 173, Folder 44)
    - Jobs Not Battleships, 1940 (Box 173, Folder 45)
    - The War's Greatest Scandal: The Story of Jim Crow in Uniform, 1943 (Box 173, Folder 46)
    - Substandard Wages, 1944 (Box 173, Folder 47)
    - The Avery Formula, 1944 (Box 173, Folder 48)
    - Half a Million Forgotten People, 1944 (Box 173, Folder 49)
    - Parodies: An Anthology from Chaucer to Beerbohm-and After, 1960 (Box 173, Folder 50)
    - Our Invisible Poor, 1963 (Box 173, Folder 51)
    - Dwight Macdonald on Movies (Box 173, Folder 51)
      - Drafts and proofs, 1969 (Box 173, Folder 52)
      - Unused material, 1969 (Box 173, Folder 53-54)
      - Notes, Undated (Box 173, Folder 55)
    - My Past and Thoughts: The Memoirs of Alexander Herzen, 1973 (Box 173, Folder 56)
    - Book on Rudyard Kipling: notes and drafts, 1973 (Box 174, Folder 57)
    - "Our Elizabeth Movies," The Miscellany, 1929 December (Box 174, Folder 58)
    - Review of For Lancelot Andrews by T.S. Eliot and The Tragedy of King Richard the Third by William Shakespeare, The Miscellany, 1930 (Box 174, Folder 59)
    - "The Modern Theater: An Inquest," The Miscellany, 1930 March (Box 174, Folder 60)
    - Reviews of Memoirs of a Sportsman by Ivan Turgenieff, by Jean-Richard Bloch, and The Women of Andros by Thornton Wilder, The Miscellany, 1930 May (Box 174, Folder 61)
    - "Robinson Jeffers," The Miscellany, 1930 July (Box 174, Folder 62)
    - "Robinson Jeffers: II," The Miscellany, 1930 September (Box 174, Folder 63)
    - The Miscellany, 1930 November (Box 174, Folder 64)
    - "Eisenstein, Pudovkin and Others," The Miscellany, 1931 March (Box 174, Folder 65)
    - "Notes on Hollywood Directors," The Symposium, 1933 April (Box 174, Folder 66)
    - "Notes on Hollywood Directors, Part II," The Symposium, 1933 July (Box 174, Folder 67)
    - "Pittsburgh: What a City Shouldn't Be," Forum, 1938 August (Box 174, Folder 68)
    - "A Letter to Leon Trotsky," Labor Power, 1939 July (Box 174, Folder 69)
    - "Metamorphic Merchant," The New Yorker, 1939 July 8 (Box 174, Folder 70)
    - "The Monopoly Committee: A Study in Frustration," The American Scholar, 1939 Summer (Box 174, Folder 71)
    - "Army Man at Work," The New Yorker, 1940 February 10, 17 (Box 174, Folder 72)
    - "Wilson vs. Roosevelt: Reflections on a Charter," New Essays, 1943 Spring (Box 174, Folder 73)
    - "The Future of Democratic Values," Horizon, 1943 November (Box 174, Folder 74)
    - "The Truth About the Greek Crisis!" politics, 1945 January (Box 174, Folder 75)
    - "An Essay on War Guilt," reprint from politics with additions, 1945 March (Box 174, Folder 76)
    - "A Worse World Order," Common Sense, 1945 May (Box 174, Folder 77)
    - "Toward a New Concept of Political Action," conclusion of "The Root of Man," politics, 1946 July (Box 174, Folder 78)
    - "White Sales and Aristotle," The New Yorker, 1952 February 2, 9 (Box 174, Folder 79)
    - "The Foolish Things of the World," The New Yorker, 1952 October 4, 11 (Box 174, Folder 80)
    - "The Book-of-the-Millenium Club," The New Yorker, 1952 November 29 (Box 174, Folder 81)
    - Review of The Complete Greed, compiled by Herman G. Weinberg: Drafts, 1952 (Box 174, Folder 82)
    - "How to Deal with Communist Subversion," discussion by Daniel Bell, Dwight Macdonald and Quincy Wright, The University of Chicago Round Table, 1952 June 29 (Box 174, Folder 83)
    - "The Defense of Everybody", 1953 July 11, 18 (Box 174, Folder 84)
    - "Cit," The New Yorker, 1953 August 22 (Box 175, Folder 85)
    - Review of The Captive Mind by Czelaw Milosz The New Yorker, 1953 November 7 (Box 175, Folder 86)
    - "The Bible in Modern Undress," The New Yorker, 1953 November 14 (Box 175, Folder 87)
    - "Action on West Fifty-Third Street," The New Yorker, 1953 December 12, 19 (Box 175, Folder 88)
    - Reviews of The Little River Anthology and New Directions 14, The New Yorker, 1954 January 23 (Box 175, Folder 89)
    - "Howtoism," The New Yorker, 1954 May 22 (Box 175, Folder 90)
    - Review of Chinese Garden: The Story of a Hero by Lawrence and Elizabeth Hanson, The New Yorker, 1954 September 18 (Box 175, Folder 91)
    - Review of Melbourne by Lord David Cecil, The New Yorker, 1955 March 12 (Box 175, Folder 92)
    - "The Wall," Exeter's Best, 1955 May (Box 175, Folder 93)
    - "The Foundation," The New Yorker, 1955 November 26-December 17 (Box 175, Folder 94)
    - Review of The Russian Revolution by N.N. Sukhanov, The New Yorker, 1956 February 18 (Box 175, Folder 95)
    - Review of The Outsider by Colin Wilson, The New Yorker, 1956 October 13 (Box 175, Folder 96)
    - Review of A Death in the Family by James Agee, The New Yorker, 1957 November 16 (Box 175, Folder 97)
    - "The Triumph of Fact," The Anchor Review, 1957 (Box 175, Folder 98)
    - Review of Film as Art by Rudolph Arnheim, The New Yorker, 1958 March 15 (Box 175, Folder 99)
    - Review of Modern English Usage by H.W. Fowler, The New Yorker, 1958 May 17 (Box 175, Folder 100)
    - "A Caste, A Culture, A Market," The New Yorker, 1958 November 22, 29 (Box 175, Folder 101)
    - "No Art and No Box Office", 1958-1959 (Box 175, Folder 102)
    - "Trotsky, Orwell and Socialism," The New Yorker, 1958 March 28 (Box 175, Folder 103)
    - Review of The Gnostic Religion by Hans Jonas, The New Yorker, 1959 October 3 (Box 175, Folder 104)
    - Review of The Art of the Essay, edited by Leslie Fiedler, The New Yorker, 1959 (Box 175, Folder 105)
    - Review of The Critical Writings of James Joyce by Richard Ellman, The New Yorker, 1959 December 12 (Box 175, Folder 106)
    - "Mark Twain: An Unsentimental Journey," The New Yorker, 1960 April 9 (Box 175, Folder 107)
    - Review of The Americans by Robert Frank, The New Yorker, 1960 May 14 (Box 175, Folder 108)
    - Reader responses to Esquire movie reviews, 1960 August (Box 175, Folder 109)
    - "Massachusetts vs. Mailer," The New Yorker, 1960 October 8 (Box 175, Folder 110)
    - Interview of Dwight Macdonald by Mike Tracey, Motion, 1961 Summer (Box 175, Folder 111)
    - Esquire film columns, 1960 (Box 175, Folder 112)
    - "Masscult & Midcult", 1961 (Box 175, Folder 113)
    - Esquire film columns, 1961 (Box 175, Folder 114)
    - "The String Untuned," The New Yorker, 1962 March 10 (Box 175, Folder 115)
    - "The First Editions of T. J. Wise," The New Yorker, 1962 November 10 (Box 175, Folder 116)
    - Esquire film columns, 1962 (Box 175, Folder 117)
    - "Our Elizabethan Movies-A Revival," Film Society, 1963 (Box 175, Folder 118)
    - Esquire columns, 1963 (Box 175, Folder 119)
    - "Mark Twain: An Unsentimental Journey," Discussions of Mark Twain, 1963 (Box 175, Folder 120)
    - Critique of Time, Fact, 1964 January-February (Box 175, Folder 121)
    - "A Theory of Mass Culture," Diogenes, 1953 Summer (Box 175, Folder 122)
    - Comments on the distinction between a reviewer and a critic, 1964 Spring (Box 176, Folder 123)
    - Esquire columns, 1964 (Box 176, Folder 124)
    - Letter to the editor on Poe, The New Leader, 1965 February 15 (Box 176, Folder 125)
    - "Writings and Writers Today," (discussion with Norman Podhoretz, Dwight Macdonald, Irving Hoew and Elizabeth Hardwick), Glamour, 1965 July (Box 176, Folder 126)
    - Review of Hollywood Babylon by Kenneth Anger: Draft, 1965 (Box 176, Folder 127)
    - Letter to the editor, Teachers College Record, 1967 March (Box 176, Folder 128)
    - "Agee and the Movies," Film Heritage, 1967 Fall (Box 176, Folder 129)
    - Esquire columns (incomplete), 1967 (Box 176, Folder 130)
    - "Confrontation: The Old Left and the New" (Daniel Aaron, Tom Hayden, Ivanhoe Donaldson, Richard Rovere and Dwight McDonald), The American Scholar, 1967 Autumn (Box 176, Folder 131)
    - International Design Conference in Aspen, "The Rest of Our Lives", 1969 June (Box 176, Folder 132)
    - "The Bible in Modern Undress," Literary Style of the Old Bible and the New, 1970 (Box 176, Folder 133)
    - Letter to the editor re "Dwight Macdonald's Revisiting Dorothy Day", 1971 February (Box 176, Folder 134)
    - "Revisiting Dorothy Day," Intellectual Digest, 1971 March-April (Box 176, Folder 135)
    - Review of Our Gang, by Philip Roth: Draft, 1971 (Box 176, Folder 136)
    - "The Metaphysics of Bureaucratic Psychology", 1971 (Box 176, Folder 137)
    - "Commentary on A Glommentary," The New Yorker, 1972 May 6 (Box 176, Folder 138)
    - Interview with Dwight Macdonald, Film Heritage, 1972 Spring (Box 176, Folder 139)
    - "The Great East Hampton Library Mess," American Libraries, 1972 September (Box 176, Folder 140)
    - "Norman Cousins' Midcult World," The Columbia Forum, 1972 Fall (Box 176, Folder 141)
    - "Conservative Anarchism: An Interview with Dwight Macdonald," The Humanist, 1973 July-August (Box 176, Folder 142)
    - "Macdonald expounds on Nixon's present situation," The Spectrum, 1973 November 12 (Box 176, Folder 143)
    - "Updating the Constitution of the United States," Esquire, 1974 May (Box 176, Folder 144)
    - Review of Essays and Afterthoughts ,by Dwight Macdonald, by Roger Sale, The New York Times Book Review, 1974 November 3 (Box 177, Folder 145)
    - Review of Scoundrel Time by Lillian Hellman, by Joseph Shattan: Annotated copy (Box 177, Folder 146)
    - "On Movies," Readings in Critical Writing, 1978 (Box 177, Folder 147)
    - Interviewing Dwight Macdonald, by Diana Trilling, 1979 Spring (Box 177, Folder 148)
    - Letter to the editor, The New York Times, 1981 August 9 (Box 177, Folder 149)
    - Review of "On Movies" by Dwight Macdonald, by John Simon, Film Comment, 1982 July-August (Box 177, Folder 150)
    - Argus, "Nathaniel Hawthorne: Writer of Romances, undated (Box 177, Folder 151)
    - Blacks, 1967-1968 (Box 177, Folder 152)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1941-1942, undated (Box 177, Folder 153)
    - Chaplin, Charles, 1964 (Box 177, Folder 154)
    - Civil disobedience, 1967-1968, undated (Box 177, Folder 155-57)
    - Detective fiction: notes, undated (Box 177, Folder 158)
    - Dupee, Frederick W., "The Trotyskyist Intellectuals": Interview, 1973 (Box 177, Folder 159)
    - English language, 1961-1966, undated (Box 177, Folder 160)
    - European anarchist groups, 1946 (Box 177, Folder 161)
    - Films
      - General, 1937-1980 (Box 177, Folder 162-165)
      - Antonioni, Michelangelo, 1960-1965 (Box 178, Folder 166-167)
      - Bresson, Robert, 1960-1963 (Box 178, Folder 168)
      - "Citizen Kane", 1963-1973 (Box 178, Folder 169)
      - "Cleopatra", 1963 (Box 178, Folder 170)
      - Conference on film, 1975 (Box 178, Folder 171)
      - DeAntonio, Emile, 1964-1975 (Box 178, Folder 172)
      - Disney, Walt, 1940-1965, undated (Box 178, Folder 173)
      - "Entr'acte" and "Ballet Mechanique", undated (Box 178, Folder 174)
      - Fellini, Federico, 1964-1966 (Box 178, Folder 175)
      - Godard, Jean-Luc, 1961-1969 (Box 178, Folder 176)
      - "A Hard Day's Night", 1964 (Box 178, Folder 177)
      - Hitchcock, Alfred, 1961-1963, undated (Box 178, Folder 178)